SERGIO RUIZ

FULLSTACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

serginator@gmail.com http://www.serginator.com

FullStack JavaScript developer with 5+ years industry experience, since the age of 6 with computers and since the age of 12 dealing with code, with strong skills in code quality, performance and continuous integration. Capacity to learn new languages and adaptability to new environments in no time thanks to his overall knowledge of languages and operative systems.

SKILLS

WEB HTML5 CSS3 JAVASCRIPT REST AJAX

JAVASCRIPT JQUERY ANGULARJS NODE.JS ZEPTO.JS UNDERSCORE

CI JENKINS SONAR GRUNT.JS UNIX DOCKER

DATABASES MYSQL SQLITE NOSQL MONGODB

SCM GIT GITHUB SVN TFS

EMPLOYMENT

Analyst Programmer, AURIGAE

2012-12 — Present

Software Developer at Telefónica I+D. I've worked mainly focused in full-stack javascript, continuous integration and evangelist of best practices, most of the time at video area.

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Unix AngularJS Mocha Sinon Chai LESS Git Github Scrum JIRA Jenkins Grunt.js Jasmine Google Cast SDK SVN jQuery SVG Sonar AJAX Node.js APS POA PBA Clean Code video opentv dth cable vod pvr stb

Systems Integration Consultant - Programmer, CIBER

2012-01 — 2012-12

Programmer at System Integration, I've been developing a social network, Android apps, rest services at BBVA GAE project, sites with Google Sites for internal documentation at BBVA and Telepizza's mobile app. HTML HTML5 CSS CSS3 JavaScript PHP ELGG Android GAE Java Google Sites C# ASP.NET MVC 4 Zepto.js jQuery AJAX JSON REST Apache nginx

Systems Integration Consultant - Junior Programmer, CIBER Junior Programmer at System Integration developing a social network. HTML CSS JavaScript AJAX PHP ELGG MySQL Unix

2011-06 — 2011-12

PROJECTS

Creator, JS Test Lab An arcade machine JavaScript HTML5 CSS3 2011-03 — Present

Developer, Movistar TV - DTH Hybrid

2015-01 — Present

Development of the UI of a set-top box (STB) with satellital and internet connection for TVApps and VOD, using SVG and JavaScript to communicate with the middleware. Also I've installed and configured all the continuous integration environment with Jenkins and Sonar, and made the Grunt.js tasks to automate everything, from linting or testing to opening pull requests automagically integrating Crowdin with new translations from the OBs.

JavaScript jQuery jasmine AJAX SVG Unix Jenkins Sonar Docker Scrum JIRA SVN Git Github video opentv dth cable vod pvr stb

Developer, Movistar TV - GO

2015-02 — 2015-03

Movistar TV web application, which allows to watch Live TV and VOD content, and handle your subscriptions, view the EPG and more. Joined the team for one month to speed development of new features.

JavaScript AngularJS Mocha Sinon Chai HTML5 CSS3 LESS AJAX Git Github Scrum JIRA Jenkins Grunt.js video vod pvr

Main developer, Movistar TV - Chromecast Receiver

2015-01 — Present

Chromecast Receiver for the mobile applications of Movistar TV, which handles to play Live TV and VOD on Chromecast. Developed in Angular JS. Also installed and configured all the continuous integration environment with Jenkins and Sonar, and made the Grunt.js tasks to automate everything, from linting or testing to opening pull requests automagically integrating Crowdin with new translations from the OBs. JavaScript AngularJS Jasmine HTML5 CSS3 Google Cast SDK AJAX Jenkins Sonar Grunt.js Docker video

Main developer, CSB - Cloud Service Broker

2014-01 — 2014-11

CSB is a panel to manage users, assign resources or services, handle your account as a user... It uses Parallels (POA and PBA). Development of an APS 1.2 to integrate McAfee Multi Access in CSB, front-end (in Dojo Toolkit) and back-end (in Node.js), for O2 (UK and GER) and VIVO (Brazil). Also made all the ci environment.

JavaScript HTML CSS Node.js Mocha Sinon Chai AJAX APS 1.2 POA PBA Scrum JIRA Git Github Unix Jenkins Grunt.js

Developer, FeedApp

2013-07 — 2014-02

Web application made with the magic of Meteor.js and Lungo.js, connected to our internal LDAP server to handle logins. After finishing it, we ported all the Lungo.js part to Firefox building blocks as some of the members of the team were members of Firefox OS and wanted to use it in their devices. This app allows to send feedback to people personally or anonymously about projects, behaviour...

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Lungo.js Meteor.js Git Github LDAP

Developer, Movistar TV - DTH Hybrid

2012-12 — 2013-12

Development of the UI of a set-top box (STB) with satellital and internet connection for TVApps and VOD, using SVG and JavaScript to communicate with the middleware. Also I've installed and configured all the continuous integration environment with Jenkins and Sonar, and made the Grunt.js tasks to automate everything, from linting or testing to opening pull requests automagically integrating Crowdin with new translations from the OBs.

JavaScript jQuery jasmine AJAX SVG Unix Jenkins Sonar Scrum JIRA SVN Git Github video opentv dth cable vod pvr stb

Developer, Telepizza - Mobile app development

2012-09 — 2012-12

Development of the Smartphone/Tablet application, with our own javascript framework to load all sections dynamically in a single page application.

C# ASP.NET MVC 4 HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Zepto.js jQuery AJAX TFS

Developer, BBVA - Google App Engine (GAE) Team

2012-06 — 2012-09

Development of services and apps for BBVA using Google App Engine (GAE). After the development of several REST services, I created some documentation webs for internal projects using Google Sites and developing gadgets in Google Apps Script.

Java Google App Engine REST JavaScript JSON Google Sites Google Apps Script PSD to HTML5/4 and CSS3/2

Main developer, HEEL - Android application

2012-02 — 2012-02

Development of a tablet application (Android) for a pharmaceutical laboratory. This app is used to let pharmacists to fill and sign contracts of sale and purchase, with a pharmacy database. It captures the form as a digital image and stores the filled form in CVS format to post-process it. lava Android SDK SQLite

Developer, TUYYOU - Development of a Social Network

2011-06 — 2012-06

Social network development using ELGG and modifying it's core. It was running for several years, being announced in several media around the country.

Coursera,

Graded

at

PHP ELGG JavaScript JSON AJAX jQuery MySQL HTML CSS Unix LAMP SVN Photoshop CS5 PSD to HTML/CSS Croww browsing (included IE7

EDUCATION

Web development with Node.js, Imagina Formación

2016-09 — 2016-10

Node.js course

nodejs javascript html5 bootstrap mongodb express tdd optimization heroku deployment

Responsive Frameworks, Imagina Formación

2016-02 — 2016-04

Responsive Frameworks course

rwd javascript html5 css3 base bootstrap foundation

Web development with Angular JS, Imagina Formación

2015-12 — 2016-02

Angular JS course

course

Α

angularjs javascript html5 css3 animations

by

An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python, Rice University

University

2013-01 — 2013-01

distinction:

with

https://www.coursera.org/records/XKhb4VhWeYRPvHnc

Rice

game development python

Software development for Android devices, Universidad Nacional de

2011-01 — 2012-01

Educación a Distancia - UNED

Android development

Android UX Programming Design

Dreamweaver CS4, Universidad Complutense de Madrid - UCM

2010-01 — 2010-01

Course certified by UCM about HTML4, CSS2 and Dreamweaver.

Engineering in Computer Science, Universidad Complutense de

2005-10 — 2010-12

Madrid - UCM

Studied Engineering in Computer Science until 3rd grade, passed all programming labs.

AFFILIATION

Co-Organizer and member, MadridJS Meetup

2011-08 — Present

Co-Organizer of MadridJS, helping with talks and organization but with the lack of time, just member since 2015

Member, HTML5 Spain Meetup Member of HTML5 Spain 2012-02 — Present

Study group formed by several members of the JavaScript community in Madrid to learn and debate about JavaScript ecosystem.

SPEAKING

Game development in JavaScript, MadridJS Meetup

2012

It was a conference Carlos and I did about Game Development in JavaScript. It was in CAMON, with around 90 attendees. Here is the video, slides and info about the session.

Workshop: Game programming in JavaScript, GameMe5

2013

Advanced workshop on how to develop a game without libraries, plain JavaScript, for the GameMe5 event. In this workshop we showed and explained in four hours, step by step, a shootem up demo. The game can be played here and the repo with more info can be watched here.